Guide to the Roe Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Missionary Photographs, 1860-1940; Series X; 6.5' (13 boxes)
  Series X, MISSIONARY PHOTOGRAPHS, is contained in Boxes 103-115. The series has been divided into three sections. The first, Missions of the Reformed Church in America (Boxes 103-107), is arranged alphabetically by name of mission and by subject under each mission. Indians of North America, section two, (Boxes 107-108), is arranged alphabetically by subject. The third section, Latin America (Boxes 109-111), has two parts, the first of which is alphabetical by country. This is followed by photographs from Mary Wickham Roe's 1925 South American trip, which has been placed together and arranged alphabetically by country. Box 112 contains glass negatives.
  Oversize material has been placed in Boxes 113-15. Oversize Family Papers and Oversize Family Photographs are arranged by name of family member. Oversize Missionary Photographs are organized alphabetically by subject.
  - Missions of the Reformed Church in America
    - Colony Mission
      See also: box 115, folders 1984-1989
      - Albums, Undated (Box 103, Folder 1806-1810)
      - Camp-meetings, 1905, 1909, undated (Box 103, Folder 1811)
      - Indian portraits, B-H, Undated (Box 103, Folder 1812)
      - Indian portraits, H-W, unidentified, Undated (Box 104, Folder 1813-1816)
      - Indians in groups, Undated (Box 104, Folder 1817)
      - Missionary portraits, Undated (Box 104, Folder 1818-1822)
      - Printed photographs, Undated (Box 104, Folder 1823)
      - "Prints to Keep" (Roe, Mary Wickham), Undated (Box 104, Folder 1824)
      - Views, 1917, undated (Box 104, Folder 1825-1828)
      - Views, 1900 (Box 105, Folder 1829)
    - Comanche Mission-Lawton Station
      - Portraits, undated (Box 106, Folder 1830)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 106, Folder 1831)
    - Dulce-Jicarilla Mission
      - Camp-meetings, 1916 (Box 106, Folder 1832)
      - Indian portraits, 1916 (Box 106, Folder 1833)
      - Postcards, undated (Box 106, Folder 1834)
      - "Trip of 1916" (Box 106, Folder 1835)
      - Views, undated (Box 106, Folder 1836)
    - Ft. Sill-Apache Mission
      - Albums, undated (Box 106, Folder 1837-1838)
      - Cavalryman, undated (Box 106, Folder 1839)
      - Ghost Dance, undated (Box 106, Folder 1840)
      - Indian portraits, D - W and unidentified, undated (Box 106, Folder 1841-1843)
      - Indians in groups, undated (Box 106, Folder 1844)
      - Views, undated (Box 106, Folder 1845)
    - Mescalero Mission
      - Indian portraits, A - W and unidentified, undated (Box 106, Folder 1846-1847)
      - Indians in groups, undated (Box 107, Folder 1848)
      - Missionary portraits, undated (Box 107, Folder 1849)
      - Views, 1916, undated (Box 107, Folder 1850-1854)
    - Winnebago Mission
      - Indian portraits, B - W and unidentified, undated (Box 107, Folder 1855-1858)
      - Indians in groups, undated (Box 107, Folder 1859)
      - Medicine Dance, undated (Box 107, Folder 1860)
      - Missionary portraits, undated (Box 107, Folder 1861-1863)
      - Views, undated (Box 107, Folder 1864-1866)
  - Indians of North America
    - Buildings, unidentified, undated (Box 107, Folder 1867-1868)
    - Eskimos, undated (Box 107, Folder 1869)
    - Indian camps, unidentified, undated (Box 107, Folder 1870-1872)
    - Indian portraits
      - Children, identified and unidentified, undated (Box 107, Folder 1873-1876)
      - Men, identified and unidentified, undated (Box 108, Folder 1877-1881)
      - Women, identified and unidentified, undated (Box 108, Folder 1882-1885)
    - Indians in groups, unidentified, undated (Box 108, Folder 1886-1892)
    - Missionaries in groups, undated (Box 108, Folder 1893)
    - Mohonk Lodge, 1901-1940 (Box 108, Folder 1894)
      See also: box 115, folder 1991
    - Postcards, undated (Box 108, Folder 1895)
    - Roe Indian Institute, 1915 (Box 108, Folder 1896)
    - Views, unidentified, undated (Box 108, Folder 1897-1900)
  - Latin America
    - Bolivia, 1930 (Box 109, Folder 1901)
    - Brazil, undated (Box 109, Folder 1902)
    - "Central America, 1922" (Roe, Mary Wickham) (Box 109, Folder 1903)
    - Chile, Costa Rica, Undated, 1928 (Box 109, Folder 1904)
    - El Salvador, undated (Box 109, Folder 1905)
    - Guatemala
      - Photographs, 1918-1939, undated (Box 109, Folder 1906-1911)
      - Postcards
        - Antigua, undated (Box 109, Folder 1912)
        - Indians, undated (Box 109, Folder 1913-1914)
        - Views, undated (Box 109, Folder 1915-1920)
    - Honduras
      - Photographs, 1920's (Box 109, Folder 1921-1922)
      - Postcards, undated (Box 109, Folder 1923-1924)
    - Mexico
      See also: box 115, folder 1992
      - Photographs, 1922-1935, undated (Box 110, Folder 1925-1931)
      - Postcards, undated (Box 110, Folder 1932-1940)
    - Peru, undated (Box 110, Folder 1941-1943)
    - South American Trip, 1925 (Roe, Mary Wickham)
      - Argentina, postcards, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 1944)
      - Bolivia, postcards, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 1945)
      - Brazil
        - Rio de Janeiro, photographs and postcards, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 1946)
        - Sao Paolo, postcards, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 1947)
        - Souvenir books, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 1948)
      - Chile
        - Photographs, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1949)
        - Postcards, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1950-1052)
      - Lansing's photos", 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1953)
      - Legters, Brainerd, photographs from trip, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1954)
      - Panama, postcards, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1955)
      - Peru
        - Photographs, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1956)
        - Postcards
          - Cuzco, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1957-1959)
          - Views, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1960-1961)
      - Uruguay, photographs and postcards, 1925 (Box 111, Folder 1962)
    - Unidentified - Latin America, undated (Box 111, Folder 1963-1965)
    - Glass negatives, undated (Box 112, Folder 1966)
  - Oversize Family Papers
    - Blueprints for Manchester house, undated (Box 113, Folder 1967)
    - Roe, Alfred Cox
      - Civil War records, 1863-1864 (Box 114, Folder 1968)
    - Roe, Joseph Wickham
      - Genealogical records, undated (Box 114, Folder 1969)
      - Painting - "Sierra Madre", undated (Box 114, Folder 1970)
    - Roe, Mary Abigail
      - Paintings - "California Wild Flowers", undated (Box 114, Folder 1971)
      - Plaques on cardboard, undated (Box 114, Folder 1972)
  - Oversize Family Photographs
    - Roe, Alfred Cox, 1900 (Box 114, Folder 1973)
    - Roe, Emma Wickham, 1860, 1900 (Box 114, Folder 1974-1975)
    - Roe, Joseph Wickham, 1895, undated (Box 114, Folder 1976-1978)
    - Roe, Joseph Wickham - album, 1895-1927, undated (Box 114, Folder 1979)
    - Roe, Mary Abigail, undated (Box 114, Folder 1980)
    - Wickham, Joseph Dresser, undated (Box 115, Folder 1981)
    - Unidentified portraits, undated (Box 115, Folder 1982)
    - U.S. - Vermont - Manchester, undated (Box 115, Folder 1983)
  - Oversize Missionary Photographs
    - Colony Mission
      - Album, undated (Box 115, Folder 1984)
      - Colony school, undated (Box 115, Folder 1985)
      - Indian child, undated (Box 115, Folder 1986)
      - Missionaries, 1905 (Box 115, Folder 1987)
      - Seger School employees, Circa 1900 (Box 115, Folder 1988)
      - Views, 1895 (Box 115, Folder 1989)
    - Mescalero Mission - "Lizard and wife", undated (Box 115, Folder 1990)
    - Mohonk Lodge, undated (Box 115, Folder 1991)
    - Mexico - Students of the National Indian School, undated (Box 115, Folder 1992)
    - Framed photographs of Joseph Wickham Roe teaching, undated (Box 115, Folder 1993)
- Indian Book Collection, 1870-1956; Series XI; 16.5' (40 boxes)
  Series XI, the INDIAN BOOK COLLECTION, is housed in Boxes 116-155. The books have been arranged alphabetically by author, and by title where the author is unknown. Authors having an asterisk (*) before their names are represented in MISSIONARY CORRESPONDENCE and MISSIONARY PAPERS.
  - Abel, Annie H., ed. The Official Correspondence of James S. Calhoun, 1915 (Box 116, Folder 1994)
  - Alger, Abby. In Indian Tents, 1897 (Box 116, Folder 1995)
  - Among the Pines; or, the Mission to the Pima and Maricopa Indians, 1895 (Box 116, Folder 1996)
  - Arctander, John W. The Apostle of Alaska, 1909 (Box 116, Folder 1997)
  - Bandelier, Ad. F. The Delight Makers, undated (Box 117, Folder 1998)
  - Barce, Elmore. The Land of the Miamis., 1922 (Box 117, Folder 1999)
  - Barrett, S.M. Geronimo's Story of his Life, 1906 (Box 117, Folder 2000)
  - Barton, Winifred S. John P. Williamson, 1919 (Box 118, Folder 2001)
  - Beach, Harlan F. Renaissant Latin America, 1916 (Box 118, Folder 2002)
  - Bliss, E.F., trans., Diary of David Zeisberger, Vol. II, 1885 (Box 118, Folder 2003)
  - Bliss, E.F., trans., Diary of David Zeisberger, Vol. II, 1885 (Box 118, Folder 2004)
  - Bourke, John G. On the Border with Crook, 1892 (Box 119, Folder 2005)
  - Bowman, Isaiah. The Andes of Southern Peru, 1916 (Box 119, Folder 2006)
  - Brooks, Elbridge. The Story of the American Indian, 1887 (Box 119, Folder 2007)
  - Brown, Hubert W. Latin America. The Pagans, the Papists … and the Present Problem, 1901 (Box 120, Folder 2008)
  - Browning, Webster E. New Days in Latin America, 1925 (Box 120, Folder 2009)
  - Bryce, James. South America: Observations and Impressions, 1913 (Box 120, Folder 2010)
  - Butler, Eva L. Two Little Navajos Dip their Sheep, 1937 (Box 120, Folder 2011)
  - Butler, John Wesley. Mexico Coming into Light, 1907 (Box 120, Folder 2012)
  - Butler, William. Mexico in Transition, 1892 (Box 121, Folder 2013)
  - Calles, Plutarco Elias. Mexico Before the World, 1927 (Box 121, Folder 2014)
  - Carson, W.E. Mexico: the Wonderland of the South, 1909 (Box 121, Folder 2015)
  - Catlin, George. The North American Indians, Vol. I, 1903 (Box 122, Folder 2016)
  - Catlin, George. The North American Indians, Vol. II, 1903 (Box 122, Folder 2017)
  - Chase, Stuart. Mexico: A Study of Two Americas, 1931 (Box 122, Folder 2018)
  - Clark, Francis E. The Continent of Opportunity, 1907 (Box 123, Folder 2019)
  - Clark, Francis E. The Gospel in Latin Lands, 1909 (Box 123, Folder 2020)
  - Clark, W.P. Indian Sign Language, 1885 (Box 123, Folder 2021)
  - Cook, William Azel. Through the Wilderness of Brazil, 1909 (Box 124, Folder 2022)
  - *Crawford, Isabel. Kiowa: story of a Blanket Indian Mission, 1915 (Box 124, Folder 2023)
  - Davis, Britton. The Truth about Geronimo, 1929 (Box 124, Folder 2024)
  - Dellenbaugh, Frederick. The North Americans of Yesterday, 1901 (Box 125, Folder 2025)
  - Dengler, Hermann. American Indians: Tribes of the Prairies and the East, 1923 (Box 125, Folder 2026)
  - Dixon, Joseph. The Vanishing Race, 1913 (Box 125, Folder 2027)
  - Doddridge, Joseph. Notes on the Settlement and Indian Wars of the Western Part of Virginia and Pennsylvania, 1876 (Box 125, Folder 2028)
  - Dodge, Richard I. Our Wild Indians, 1890 (Box 126, Folder 2029)
  - Dorsey, George. Indians of the Southwest, 1903 (Box 126, Folder 2030)
  - Drannan, William A. Thirty-One Years on the Plains and in the Mountains, 1900 (Box 126, Folder 2031)
  - Eastman, Charles A. Indian Boyhood, 1902 (Box 126, Folder 2032)
  - Eastman, Charles A. Old Indian Days, 1907 (Box 127, Folder 2033)
  - Eastman, Charles A. The Soul of the Indian, 1911 (Box 127, Folder 2034)
  - Eaton, Rachel C. John Ross and the Cherokee Indians, 1914 (Box 127, Folder 2035)
  - Eells, Myron. History of Indian Missions on the Pacific Coast, 1882 (Box 127, Folder 2036)
  - Elliott, L.E. Central America: New Paths in Ancient Lands, 1925 (Box 128, Folder 2037)
  - Finerty, John F. Warpath and Bivouac: or, the Conquest of the Sioux, 1890 (Box 128, Folder 2038)
  - Fletcher, Alice C. Indian Story and Song, 1900 (Box 128, Folder 2039)
  - Franck, Harry A. Vagabonding Down the Andes, 1920 (Box 129, Folder 2040)
  - Fynn, A.J. The American Indian as a Product of Environment, 1907 (Box 129, Folder 2041)
  - Gammon, Samuel. The Evangelical Invasion of Brazil, 1910 (Box 129, Folder 2042)
  - Gilfallen, Joseph. The Ojibway: A Novel of Indian Life, 1904 (Box 130, Folder 2043)
  - Glass, Fred C. Through the Heart of Brazil, .undated (Box 130, Folder 2044)
  - Graham, R.B.C. The Conquest of New Granada, 1922 (Box 130, Folder 2045)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Cheyenne Indians. Vol. I, 1923 (Box 130, Folder 2046)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Cheyenne Indians. Vol. II, 1923 (Box 131, Folder 2047)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Fighting Cheyennes, 1915 (Box 131, Folder 2048)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Indians of Today, 1940 (Box 131, Folder 2049)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Punishment of the Stingy and Other Indian Stories, 1901 (Box 132, Folder 2050)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Story of the Indian, 1898 (Box 132, Folder 2051)
  - Grinnell, George Bird. The Story of the Indian (copy 2), 1898 (Box 132, Folder 2052)
  - Grosse, Howard B. Advance in the Antilles, 1910 (Box 132, Folder 2053)
  - Grubb, W. Barbrooke. A Church in the Wilds, 1914 (Box 133, Folder 2054)
  - Guinness, Geraldine. Peru: Its Story, People and Religion, undated (Box 133, Folder 2055)
  - Hale, Albert. The South Americans, 1907 (Box 134, Folder 2056)
  - Haskell Institute. Indian Legends and Superstitions, 1914 (Box 134, Folder 2057)
  - Hay, Alex Rattray. Saints and Savages: Brazil's Indian Problem, undated (Box 134, Folder 2058)
  - Herbertson, E.D. and A.J. Central and South American with the West Indies, 1908 (Box 134, Folder 2059)
  - High, Stanley. Looking Ahead with Latin, America, 1925 (Box 134, Folder 2060)
  - Hinman, George. The American Indian and Christian Missions, 1933 (Box 135, Folder 2061)
  - Hulbert, Winifred. Indian Americans (2 copies), 1932 (Box 135, Folder 2062)
  - Hulst, Cornelia. Indian Sketches, 1912 (Box 135, Folder 2063)
  - Hume, Martin, ed. The South American Series: Peru, 1908 (Box 135, Folder 2064)
  - Humphrey, Seth K. The Indian Dispossessed, 1906 (Box 136, Folder 2065)
  - Humphreys, M.G. Missionary Explorers among the American Indians, 1913 (Box 136, Folder 2066)
  - *Innan, Samuel Guy. Trailing the Conquistadores, 1930 (Box 136, Folder 2067)
  - *Innan,Samuel Guy. Ventures in:Inter-American Friendship, 1925 (Box 136, Folder 2068)
  - Institute for Government Research. The Problem of Indian Administration, 1928 (Box 137, Folder 2069)
  - Institute for Government Research. The Problem of Indian Administration (copy 2), 1928 (Box 137, Folder 2070)
  - Jackson, Helen Hunt. A Century of Dishonor, 1893 (Box 138, Folder 2071)
  - Johnston, Julia. Indian and Spanish Neighbors, 1905 (Box 138, Folder 2072)
  - Jordan, W.F. Central American Indians and the Bible, 1926 (Box 138, Folder 2073)
  - Jordan, W.F. Ecuador: A Story of Mission Achievement, 1926 (Box 138, Folder 2074)
  - Jordan, W.F. Glimpses of Indian America, 1923 (Box 139, Folder 2075)
  - Kellogg, Harold and Delaine. Indians of the Southwest, 1936 (Box 139, Folder 2076)
  - Kirkham, Stanton D. Mexican Trails, 1909 (Box 139, Folder 2077)
  - *Kneale, Albert H. Indian Agent, 1950 (Box 139, Folder 2078)
  - Ladd, Horatio O. The Story of New Mexico, 1891 (Box 140, Folder 2079)
  - La Flesche, Francis. The Middle Five, 1901 (Box 140, Folder 2080)
  - *Leupp, Francis E. In Red Man's Land, 1914 (Box 140, Folder 2081)
  - *Leupp, Francis E. The Indian and his Problem, 1910 (Box 140, Folder 2082)
  - *Lindquist, G.E.E. The Jesus Road and the Red Man, 1929 (Box 141, Folder 2083)
  - *Lindquist, G.E.E. The Red Man in the United States, 1923 (Box 145, Folder 2084)
  - Love, W. DeLoss. Samson Occom and the Christian Indians of New England, 1899 (Box 145, Folder 2085)
  - Lummis, Charles F. The Awakening of a Nation: Mexico of Today, 1898 (Box 142, Folder 2086)
  - Lummis, Charles F. The Land of Poco Tiempo, 1902 (Box 142, Folder 2087)
  - McBeth, Kate C. The Nez Perces since Lewis and Clark, 1908 (Box 142, Folder 2088)
  - McClintock, Walter. Old Indian Trails, 1923 (Box 143, Folder 2089)
  - McCreight, M.I. Chief Flying Hawk's Tales, 1936 (Box 143, Folder 2090)
  - McLaughlin, James. My Friend the Indian, 1910 (Box 143, Folder 2091)
  - McLean, J.H. The Living Christ for Latin America, 1916 (Box 143, Folder 2092)
  - Magoffin, Susan S. Down the Santa Fe Trail and into Mexico, 1926 (Box 144, Folder 2093)
  - Mathews, J.J. Wah-Kon-Tah, The Osage and the White Man's Road, 1932 (Box 144, Folder 2094)
  - Means, Philip Ainsworth. Ancient Civilizations of the Andes, 1931 (Box 145, Folder 2095)
  - Meriam, Lewis. Facing the Future in Indian Missions, 1932 (Box 145, Folder 2096)
  - Michener, Carroll K. Heirs of the Incas, 1924 (Box 145, Folder 2097)
  - Moffett, Thomas C. The American Indians on the New Trail, 1914 (Box 146, Folder 2098)
  - Moorehead, Warren K. The American Indian, 1914 (Box 146, Folder 2099)
  - Morrison, William B. The Red Man's Trail, 1932 (Box 146, Folder 2100)
  - Munro, Dana G. The Five Republics of Central America, 1918 (Box 146, Folder 2101)
  - Murray, William H. Essays on Pocahontas and Pushmataha, 1924 (Box 146, Folder 2102)
  - Neely, Thomas B. South American: A Mission Field, 1906 (Box 147, Folder 2103)
  - Neely, Thomas B. South America: Its Missionary problems, 1909 (Box 147, Folder 2104)
  - Nixon, O.W. Whitman's Ride through Savage Lands, 1905 (Box 147, Folder 2105)
  - Page, Jesse. David Brainerd, undated (Box 147, Folder 2106)
  - Prodgers, C.H. Adventures in Bolivia, 1922 (Box 147, Folder 2107)
  - Quinn, Vernon. Beautiful Mexico, 1924 (Box 148, Folder 2108)
  - Remington, Frederic. The Way of an Indian, 1906 (Box 148, Folder 2109)
  - Riggs, Stephen. Mary and I: Forty Years with the Sioux, 1887 (Box 148, Folder 2110)
  - Santee, Ross. Apache Land, 1947 (Box 148, Folder 2111)
  - Schultz, James. My Life as an Indian, 1907 (Box 149, Folder 2112)
  - Schultz, James. On the Warpath, 1914 (Box 149, Folder 2113)
  - Schweintz, Edmund. The Life and Times of David Zeisberger, 1870 (Box 149, Folder 2114)
  - *Seger, John Homer. Early Days among the Cheyenne and Arapahoe Indians, 1956 (Box 150, Folder 2115)
  - Sparhawk, F.C. Senator Intrigue and Inspector Noseby, 1895 (Box 150, Folder 2116)
  - Speer, Robert. Missions in South America, undated (Box 150, Folder 2117)
  - Speer, Robert. South American Problems, 1913 (Box 150, Folder 2118)
  - Stewart, R.L. Sheldon Jackson, 1908 (Box 150, Folder 2119)
  - Stahl, F.A. In the Land of the Incas, 1920 (Box 151, Folder 2120)
  - Stuntz, Homer. South American Neighbors, 1916 (Box 151, Folder 2121)
  - Summerhayes, Martha. Vanished Arizona, 1911 (Box 151, Folder 2122)
  - Talbot, Edith A. Samuel Chapman Armstrong, 1904 (Box 151, Folder 2123)
  - Trull, George. Missionary Studies for the Sunday School (two copies), 1906 (Box 152, Folder 2124)
  - Tucker, H.C. The Bible in Brazil, 1902 (Box 152, Folder 2125)
  - Tylee, Mrs. Arthur F. The Challenge of Amazon's Indians, 1931 (Box 152, Folder 2126)
  - Wald, Eva C. Alaska, the Land of the Totem, undated (Box 152, Folder 2127)
  - Wheeler, W.R. et.al. Modern Missions in Mexico, 1925 (Box 152, Folder 2128)
  - Whipple, Henry. Lights and Shadows of a Long Episcopate, 1900 (Box 153, Folder 2129)
  - Willard, T.A. The City of the Sacred Well, 1926 (Box 153, Folder 2130)
  - Wilson, Gilbert. Goodbird the Indian, 1914 (Box 153, Folder 2131)
  - Wissler, Clark. Indians of the United States, 1940 (Box 154, Folder 2132)
  - Young, Egerton. The Apostle of the North, James Evans, 1899 (Box 154, Folder 2133)
  - Young, Egerton. Indian Wigwams and Northern Campfires, 1893 (Box 154, Folder 2134)
  - Young, Egerton. On the Indian Trail, 1897 (Box 155, Folder 2135)
  - Young, Egerton. Three Arrows, the Young Buffalo Hunter, 1932 (Box 155, Folder 2136)
- Roe Addition, 1802-1970; 4.0' (9 boxes)
  The ROE ADDITION fills Boxes 156-164 of the Roe Family Papers. There is material from six series. Series I, FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE, is chronologically arranged. Series II, FAMILY PAPERS, is alphabetically arranged by name of family member and then by type of material. Series V, PRINTED WORKS, is alphabetically arranged by author; Series VI, FAMILY PHOTOGRAPHS, alphabetically by subject; Series VII, HENRY ROE CLOUD PAPERS, is chronologically arranged; and Series IX, MISSIONARY PAPERS, is alphabetically arranged.
  - Family Correspondence, Series I
    - Correspondence, 1897-1961 (Box 156, Folder 1-22)
  - Family Papers, Series II
    - Merwin family memorabilia, 1866 (Box 157, Folder 23)
    - Merwin, Miranda B. notebook, 1917-1925 (Box 157, Folder 24)
    - Roe, Alfred C.
      - Rabboni: A Story of Jesus and His Friends -- manuscript, undated (Box 157, Folder 25-34)
      - Rabboni: A Story of Jesus and His Friends -- manuscript, undated (Box 158, Folder 35)
      - Rabboni: A Story of Jesus and His Friends -- typescript, undated (Box 158, Folder 36-45)
      - Sermon by Philips Brooks, 1880 (Box 158, Folder 46)
    - Roe, Joseph Wickham
      - Account books, 1958-1960 (Box 158, Folder 47)
      - Address books, 1957-1960 (Box 158, Folder 48)
      - Death instructions, 1959-1960 (Box 158, Folder 49)
      - Estate papers
        - Bills and receipts, 1960 (Box 158, Folder 50)
        - Correspondence (Box 158, Folder 51-52)
        - Inventories, 1934-1961 (Box 159, Folder 53-59)
        - Notes, 1960-1961 (Box 159, Folder 60)
        - Trust fund
          - Correspondence, 1959-1970 (Box 159, Folder 61)
          - Papers, 1960-1970 (Box 159, Folder 62)
      - Memorabilia of Nellie Allen Roe, 1898, undated (Box 159, Folder 63)
      - Papers, 1927-1960 (Box 159, Folder 64)
      - Power of attorney, 1959 (Box 159, Folder 65)
      - Société Religieuse des Amis, 1923, 1960 (Box 159, Folder 66)
      - Wedding book, 1902 (Box 159, Folder 67)
      - Paintbox and palette, undated (Box 160, Folder 68)
  - Printed Works, Series V
    - Burrell, Angus and Cerf, Bennett. The Bedside Book of Famous American Stories, 1936 (Box 161, Folder 69)
    - Collier, Price. Germany and the Germans from an American Point of View, 1913 (Box 161, Folder 70)
    - Edwards, Jonathan. Works. Vol I, 1802 (Box 162, Folder 71)
    - Parker, Henry Bamford. Jonathan Edwards, the Fiery Puritan, 1930 (Box 162, Folder 72)
    - Roe, Mary A. E.P. Roe: Reminiscences of his Life, 1899 (Box 162, Folder 73)
    - Roe, Willism A. An Inn for Journeying Thoughts, 1912 (Box 163, Folder 74)
    - Stefansson, Vilhajalmur. Mir Life with the Eskimo, 1913 (Box 163, Folder 75)
  - Family Photographs, Series VI
    - Albums, Circa 1902 (Box 163, Folder 76-77)
    - Merwin, Miranda B., undated (Box 164, Folder 78)
    - Roe, Alfred Cox - friends, Circa 1864 (Box 164, Folder 79)
    - Roe, Joseph Wickham, Circa 1875, 1920's (Box 164, Folder 80)
  - Henry Roe Cloud Papers, Series VII
    - "Nik-Ya-Wey News", 1941-1942 (Box 164, Folder 81)
  - Missionary Papers, Series IX
    - Women's Board of Domestic Missions -Pamphlets, 1911, 1941-1942 (Box 164, Folder 82)
    - Colony Mission
      - Camp-meetings, undated (Box 164, Folder 83)
      - "Pageant of Indian History at Colony", by Elizabeth Page Harris, undated (Box 164, Folder 84)
- Additional materials, Accession 2006-M-043
  Also includes Accession 2006-M-060 (see folder 3).
  - Correspondence, 1942-1956, undated
    - Henry Roe Cloud to Anne Woesha Cloud and her husband Robert Carver North, 1943-1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Lillian Freed to Anne Woesha Roe Cloud, 1942 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Raymond Roe Cloud/group of Pueblo Indians, Circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 4)